Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- standing at podium holding papers, jacket, tie, vest, white/gray hair parted on side, mustache, beard [Howell, William Henry, Ph.D., M.D., ScD., LL.D., Professor of Physiology and Assistant Director of the School of Hygiene and Public Health], 156820 (Item 2398)
  #2005-2007, 2022, 2249, 2250, 2274, 2275, 2398, 2399 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Howell" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- seated holding papers, jacket, tie, vest, white/gray hair parted on side, mustache, beard [Howell, William Henry, Ph.D., M.D., ScD., LL.D., Professor of Physiology and Assistant Director of the School of Hygiene and Public Health], 156819 (Item 2399)
- salt and pepper hair, straight, parted, older, mustache, suit, high collared shirt, tie, seated, book in hand [Goodnow, Frank Johnson, LL.D., President of the University, Johns Hopkins University], 156818 (Item 2400)
  #2062, 2400, 2401 same subject, this print appears to be a photogravure proof for the book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Goodnow" in DU's handwriting, mat and mount missing
- salt and pepper hair, straight, parted, older, mustache, suit, high collared shirt, tie, seated, book in hand [Goodnow, Frank Johnson, LL.D., President of the University, Johns Hopkins University], 156817 (Item 2401)
  #2062, 2400, 2401 same subject, subject is in JHU "A Book of Portraits.. .", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- medium dark curly hair, jacket, vest, high collared shirt, watch chain, standing by open drawer of a file cabinet [Coy, George J., Registrar of the Medical Department, Johns Hopkins University], 156816 (Item 2402)
- middle aged, bald, white hair, mustache, trim beard, stout, seated, in academic robes [Welch, William Henry, M.D., LL.D, Director and Head of the Department of Bacteriology and Immunology of School of Hygiene and Public Life], 156815 (Item 2403)
- middle aged, bald, white hair, mustache, trim beard, stout, seated, in academic robes [Welch, William Henry, M.D., LL.D, Director and Head of the Department of Bacteriology and Immunology of School of Hygiene and Public Life], 156814 (Item 2404)
  #1988, 1989, 2395, 2403, 2404, 2953 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Weed" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- medium dark curly hair, jacket, vest, high collared shirt, watch chain, standing by open drawer of a file cabinet [Coy, George J., Registrar of the Medical Department, Johns Hopkins University], 156813 (Item 2405)
- middle aged, medium dark thin hair, suit, tie, seated in front of an x-ray (known then as a roentgen, named after W. K. Roentgen, their discoverer) [Baetjer, Frederick Henry, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Roentgenology], 156812 (Item 2406)
  this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Baetjer" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- missing from box, 156811 (Item 2407)
- middle aged, bald, gray hair, mustache, stout, seated at desk or table with pen or pencil, suit, vest, tie [Butler, Nicholas Murray, President Columbia], 1918; 156810 (Item 2408)
  #1155, 1270, 1324, 2408, 2409, 3009 same subject; subject is in "XXIV Portraits.. ." but not this image; identification on back of mat in unknown hand
- middle aged, bald, gray hair, mustache, stout, seated, suit, vest, tie [Butler, Nicholas Murray, President Columbia], 1918; 156809 (Item 2409)
  #1155, 1270, 1324, 2408, 2409, 3009 same subject; subject is in "XXIV Portraits.. ." but not this image
- white hair, parted in middle, bushy eyebrows, herringbone suit [Holt, L. Emmett, Carpentier Professor of the Diseases of Children, Columbia Faculty], 1919; 156808 (Item 2410)
- middle aged, thinning medium light colored hair, mustache (?), suit, vest, tie, pince nez eyeglasses, 156807 (Item 2411)
- middle aged, seated at table or desk, writing, suit, tie, round eyeglasses, balding light hair [Darrach, William, Professor of Clinical Surgery, Columbia], 1919; 156806 (Item 2412)
- middle aged, white straight hair, parted on side, mustache, beard, suit, vest, tie, seated with right arm resting on ledge (?), 156805 (Item 2413)
- bald, middle aged, pleasant looking, seated with pipe, suit, vest, tie, 1919; 156804 (Item 2414)
- young, smart looking, medium dark straight hair, parted on side, slicked down, suit, vest, seated, 156803 (Item 2415)
- older, salt and pepper thinning hair, mustache, linen striped suit jacket, knit tie, seated with book, 156802 (Item 2416)
- young, medium dark slicked-back hair, parted, suit vest, tie, seated holding unlit cigarette, looking down, pensive, 156801 (Item 2417)
- older, standing, face in partial shadow, outside, white bushy mustache, in suit, vest, holding coat, no tie, tattered felt hat, 156800 (Item 2418)
- middle aged, standing in front of anvil, holding hammer and piece iron, work shirt, suspenders, mustache, rumpled felt hat, 156799 (Item 2419)
- older, heavy white and gray beard and mustache, sideburns, felt hat, overalls, denim jacket, seated, holding leather straps, 156798 (Item 2420)
- older, lined face, beard, mustache, nubby fabric long sleeved shirt, suspenders, tattered felt hat, seated outside, 156797 (Item 2421)
- young, smooth, dark or tanned complexion, work shirt, rolled up sleeves, overalls, cap, 156796 (Item 2422)
  #2422, 2488 same subject
- older, somewhat heavy white curly hair, mustache, beard, polka dot shirt, holding pen knife and pipe, 156795 (Item 2423)
  #2423, 2424, 2470, 2504, 2882-2884 same subject
- older, somewhat heavy white curly hair, mustache, beard, polka dot shirt, 156794 (Item 2424)
- older, long straight white hair, parted on side, long sideburns and handlebar mustache, work shirt with full sleeves, seated, good felt hat in lap, 156793 (Item 2425)
- older, thinning white hair, mustache, work shirt, vest, gaunt-looking, seated in hay, 156792 (Item 2426)
  #2426, 2463, 2465-2467, 2480 same subject
- older, dapper-looking, heavy white and gray mustache, round eyeglasses, felt hat, vest, work shirt, leaning on fence, very thin physique, 156791 (Item 2427)
  #2427, 2621 same subject
- older, heavy white and gray mustache, straw hat, vest, work shirt, knit cardigan, very thin physique, standing leaning on cane, 156790 (Item 2428)
- middle aged, thinning white or light colored hair, mustache, stout, dark shirt and cardigan, standing in front of large wagon wheel, 156789 (Item 2429)
- older, white hair and mustache, smartly dressed, suit jacket, vest, ribbon bow tie, seated on porch step with cane (?) or umbrella, minister (?), 156788 (Item 2430)
  #1620, 2430, 2431, 2609, 2795, 2796, 2825 same subject
- older, white hair and mustache, suit jacket, vest, bow tie, dark colored felt hat, seated, 156787 (Item 2431)
  #2430, 2431, 2609, 2795, 2796 same subject
- middle aged, white hair, sideburns, beard; dark suit jacket, no tie, felt had, seated outside, sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example), 156786 (Item 2432)
- middle aged, medium light hair, sideburns, beard; dark vest, no tie, felt hat, standing out side of barn door, sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example), 156785 (Item 2433)
  #2433, 2511 same subject
- young to middle aged, cap, dark or tanned complexion, work shirt, suspenders, cap, standing in front of or operating some kind machinery, 156784 (Item 2434)
- older, very white straight hair parted on side, very long sideburns and beard, seated, light colored work shirt, suspenders, 156783 (Item 2435)
  #2435, 2436 same subject
- older, very white straight hair parted on side, very long sideburns and beard, seated with book, light colored work shirt, suspenders, 156782 (Item 2436)
- older, white beard and mustache, large, big brimmed felt hat, suit, ribbon bow tie, dapper-looking, seated holding rolled up newspaper, 156781 (Item 2437)
  #2437-2439, 2841, 2845, 2846 same subject
- older, white beard and mustache, large, big brimmed felt hat, suit, ribbon bow tie, dapper-looking, standing holding folded newspaper, 156780 (Item 2438)
- older, white beard and mustache, large, big brimmed felt hat, suit, ribbon bow tie, dapper-looking, seated holding rolled up newspaper, 156779 (Item 2439)
- older, white and gray hair, parted in middle, beard and mustache, sideburns, seated, holding nice straw hat, smiling; sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example), 156778 (Item 2440)
- older, white and gray hair, beard and mustache, sideburns, felt hat, jacket, white work shirt, seated, 156777 (Item 2441)
- older, white hair, very long beard and mustache, sideburns, tanned complexion, work shirt, suspenders, 156776 (Item 2442)
- middle aged, large straw hat, dark work shirt, vest, striped pants, stooped on a wagon bed (?) with wood hand drill, drilling into what looks like a 2x3, 156775 (Item 2443)
- young, clean shaven, light colored hat, holding pipe in mouth, smiling, leaning on plank wall outside, paint peeling, work shirt, suspenders, belt, 156774 (Item 2444)
- older, white beard and mustache, sideburns, large-brimmed straw hat, dark collarless jacket; sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example), 156773 (Item 2445)
- middle aged, wit hair and mustache, cap, cigarette or cigar in mouth, work shirt, suspenders, apron, outside, unloading buckets of salt (?) from a wooden wagon, 156772 (Item 2446)
- middle aged, short medium dark hair, cap, mustache, rugged complexion, dark work shirt, pants, suspenders, seated on a dock, ships in background, 156771 (Item 2447)
- young, tattered straw hat, light colored work shirt, overalls, holding a broom handle, emerging from a doorway or barn, 156770 (Item 2448)
- older, tattered straw hat, bushy mustache, woven work shirt, suspenders, striped pants, seated on stool outside, 156769 (Item 2449)
- older, scraggly white or light gray hair, sideburns, mustache, dark suit, vest, tie, open book in lap, 156768 (Item 2450)
  #2450, 2451, 2483 same subject
- older, scraggly white or light gray hair, sideburns, mustache, dark suit, vest, tie, seated, holding book, 156767 (Item 2451)
- older, long face, white or light gray hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, seated holding hat, work shirt, 156766 (Item 2452)
- seated outside, older, white hair, Stetson-type felt hat, mustache, beard, suit, vest, ribbon tie, seated holding rolled up newspaper, minister (?), 156765 (Item 2453)
  #2453, 2613 same subject
- middle aged, medium dark hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, work shirt, overalls, holding hammer and tongs (blacksmith), standing in front of barn or shed, 156764 (Item 2454)
  #2454, 2457, 2458 same subject
- older, white hair, heavy mustache, dark felt beret, dark jacket, checked shirt without collar, standing in doorway, 156763 (Item 2455)
  oil pigment or oil transfer print; Xerox copy has note identifying subject as "Mr. Hoag (PWJ) oil print"
- older, white thin hair, mustache, sideburns, beard, work shirt, seated on porch, felt hat in lap, 156762 (Item 2456)
- middle aged, medium dark hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, work shirt, overalls, seated, holding hammer and another tool, 156761 (Item 2457)
- middle aged, medium dark hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, work shirt, overalls, seated, holding hammer, 156760 (Item 2458)
- middle aged, salt and pepper colored hair, a white streak around hairline, fine features, light colored suit, print shirt, pencil thin necktie, seated, cane in hands, 156759 (Item 2459)
- older, oval eyeglasses, thin hair, mustache, sideburns, felt hat, jacket, work shirt, standing on crutches, 156758 (Item 2460)
  #2460, 2490, 2692 same subject
- middle aged, light or gray short spiky hair, mustache, lean, seated, dark colored work shirt, suspenders, 156757 (Item 2461)
- middle aged to older, light colored or white hair, mustache, seated, cardigan, vest, collarless shirt, hands folded, ferns in background, 156756 (Item 2462)
- older, thinning white hair, mustache, work shirt, vest, gaunt-looking, 156755 (Item 2463)
- older, white mustache, scraggly straw hat, in sun, white undershirt, suspenders, squinting or smiling, 156754 (Item 2464)
- older, thinning white hair, mustache, work shirt, vest, gaunt-looking, seated in hay, 156753 (Item 2465)
- older, thinning white hair, mustache, work shirt, vest, gaunt-looking, seated in hay, 156752 (Item 2466)
- older, thinning white hair, mustache, work shirt, vest, gaunt-looking, seated in hay, almost smiling, 156751 (Item 2467)
- middle aged to older, white short hair, mustache, dark work shirt, vest, hand resting on doorsill of shed or barn, smiling, looking energetic and engaging, 156750 (Item 2468)
  #2468, 2481, 2491, 2798, 2842 same subject
- older, thin hair, mustache, beard, work shirt, overalls, seated in front of railing, on hand on railing, one hand on cane, potted rosemary plant on railing, 156749 (Item 2469)
- older, thick white hair, parted on side, neatly trimmed mustache and beard, polka dot shirt, seated outside of shed or barn, holding pipe, 156748 (Item 2470)
- middle aged to older, dark felt hat with wide band, work shirt, suspenders, seated in chair leaning back on to wall in background, holding folded newspaper, round eyeglasses perched on nose, 156747 (Item 2471)
- older, white hair and thick mustache, prominent nose, light colored shirt, suspenders, seated reading newspaper, 156746 (Item 2472)
- middle aged man, dark hair, white shirt, tie, suspenders, holding rolled piece of paper or booklet; boy, medium light hair, white shirt, sleeves rolled up, holding white cap; both seated in what looks like a church pew, 156745 (Item 2473)
- middle aged, seated, medium dark straight thick hair, mustache, rough complexion, seated outside in straight backed chair, gray work shirt with collar, suspenders, dark pants, arms crossed across chest, 156744 (Item 2474)
- middle aged, seated in corner by a stone wall and a shingled wall, felt hat with wide band, light colored shirt, vest, seated, holding book (bible, pastor?), 156743 (Item 2475)
  #2475, 2476 same subject
- middle aged, seated in corner by a stone wall and a shingled wall, felt hat with wide band, light colored shirt, vest, seated, holding book (bible, pastor?), 156742 (Item 2476)
- middle aged, clean shaven, felt hat, top coat, work shirt, overalls, standing in front of low trees or bushes, 156741 (Item 2477)
- older, dark felt hat, bushy mustache, light colored work shirt, suspenders, seated in sunshine, 156740 (Item 2478)
- woman, middle aged, salt and pepper straight hair pulled back, print dress; three boys, one blond, two medium dark hair; older man, very short white hair, white shirt, dark tie, suspenders; all seated in front of some bushes outside, 156739 (Item 2479)
- older, thinning white hair, mustache, work shirt, vest, gaunt-looking, seated in hay, 156738 (Item 2480)
- middle aged to older, white short hair, mustache, dark work shirt, vest, looking energetic and engaging, 156737 (Item 2481)
- older, thin medium light hair, parted on side (maybe hair is combed over bald spot), round eyeglasses, polka dot shirt, suspenders, seated, 156736 (Item 2482)
- older, scraggly white or light gray hair, sideburns, mustache, dark suit, vest, tie, 156735 (Item 2483)
- two young men; both medium dark hair, appear to be in matching medium light colored shirts, sleeves rolled up; one sitting on split rail fence, the other standing, 156734 (Item 2484)
  note on Xerox "Brasstown, N.C., John C. Campbell Folk School, Taken 1933 Summer"
- doctor, white lab jacket, tie, middle aged, short white or blonde hair, standing with hands supporting neck of patient on gurney; patient is young woman or man, head is bandaged, 156733 (Item 2485)
- slender woman, dark straight hair pulled back, white silk jacket and matching blouse or dress, seated on sofa with embroidered pillows, looks as if she is working on a needlepoint project [Coolidge, Grace Goodhue (1879-1957) (Mrs. Calvin Coolidge)], 156732 (Item 2486)
- slender woman, dark straight hair pulled back, white silk jacket and matching blouse or dress, seated on sofa with embroidered pillows, looks as if she is working on a needlepoint project [Coolidge, Grace Goodhue (1879-1957) (Mrs. Calvin Coolidge)], 156731 (Item 2487)
- young, smooth, dark or tanned complexion, work shirt, rolled up sleeves, overalls, cap, 156730 (Item 2488)
- middle aged, thick medium light straight hair, parted on side, mustache, white shirt, undershirt, suspenders, seated, cutting cane seat out of a chair with a pair of scissors, 156729 (Item 2489)
  #2489, 2502, 2503, 2509, 2510, 2587, 2588, 2821, 2837, 2874 same subject
- older, oval eyeglasses, thin hair, mustache, sideburns, felt hat, jacket, work shirt, standing on crutches, 156728 (Item 2490)
- middle aged to older, white short hair, mustache, dark work shirt, vest, seated with pipe, 156727 (Item 2491)
- older, felt hat with wide band, light colored shirt, cardigan, mustache, scraggly beard, full smile, no teeth, 156726 (Item 2492)
- fruit vendor with cart with wooden spoke wheels, in sunshine, standing, cap, holding a bunch of grapes, white shirt, tie, dark pants, 156725 (Item 2493)
  #2493, 2536 same subject
- middle aged man, in profile, short medium light hair, dark beret, mustache, seated at table or desk, thick book on table, holding smaller book, reading, dark jacket, tie, 156724 (Item 2494)
- middle aged, standing in front of some bushes, balding, mustache, suit, vest, no tie, holding a branch of flowers, 156723 (Item 2495)
- middle aged man, smiling, work shirt, medium dark hair, mustache, seated plucking feathers from a chicken which is hanging by a foot on a string, 156722 (Item 2496)
  #2496, 2586, 2589 same subject
- older, balding but somewhat thick straight salt and pepper hair, light beard, sideburns, mustache, smiling, clean work shirt, suspenders, seated with open book in lap, 156721 (Item 2497)
  #2497, 2531 same subject
- older, straw hat, light gray mustache, beard, sideburns, light colored work shirt, dark vest, seated, hands on cane, almost smiling, 156720 (Item 2498)
- young, floppy hat, thick mustache, light colored work shirt, suspenders, standing, hands in grain or feed bin, at feed store (?), with sign or poster of horse or donkey on wall, price list, etc., 156719 (Item 2499)
- middle aged to older, big straw hat, white and gray sideburns, mustache, beard, gray colored work shirt with double stitched seams, seated outside in front of doorway, holding a cane, 156718 (Item 2500)
- older, soft felt hat, medium gray work shirt, dark vest, standing with arms on a split rail fence, holding a curvy twig, 156717 (Item 2501)
- middle aged, thick medium light straight hair, parted on side, mustache, white shirt, undershirt, suspenders, seated, holding chair with cane seat, 156716 (Item 2502)
- middle aged, thick medium light straight hair, parted on side, mustache, white shirt, undershirt, suspenders, seated, holding rocking chair with cane seat, 156715 (Item 2503)
- older, lots of light or white, long hair, tousled, beard, mustache, polka dot shirt; looks like close relative of subject in 2503 (same nose and shape of face), 156714 (Item 2504)
- older, lots of light or white, long hair, tousled, beard, mustache, polka dot shirt; looks like close relative of subject in 2503 (same nose and shape of face), 156713 (Item 2505)
  #2504, 2505, 2823, 2829 same subject
- older, large straw hat, white sideburns, mustache, beard, smiling, seated, light colored work shirt, dark vest, hands on cane, 156712 (Item 2506)
  #2506-2508 same subject
- older, large straw hat, white sideburns, mustache, beard, light colored work shirt, dark vest, 156711 (Item 2507)
- older, large straw hat, white sideburns, mustache, beard, smiling, light colored work shirt, dark vest, seated, hands on cane, 156710 (Item 2508)
- middle aged, thick medium light straight hair, parted on side, mustache, white shirt, undershirt, suspenders, seated, cutting a cane seat from a chair with scissors, 156709 (Item 2509)
- middle aged, thick medium light straight hair, parted on side, mustache, white shirt, undershirt, suspenders, seated, holding a chair with a cane seat, 156708 (Item 2510)
  #2489, 2502, 2503, 2509, 2510, 2587, 2588, 2821, 2837 same subject
- middle aged, medium light hair, sideburns, beard; dark vest, no tie, felt hat, standing out side of barn door, holding a corn cob, sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example), 156707 (Item 2511)
- older, long white beard, felt hat, mustache, sideburns, seated in sunshine, dark jacket, holding a newspaper, 156706 (Item 2512)
- middle aged to older, spiky medium light hair, trim mustache and beard, striped jacket, gray colored work shirt, seated with newspaper, plants in foreground, 156705 (Item 2513)
  #2513, 2516 same subject
- middle aged, medium light hair, beard and sideburns, smiling, round eyeglasses, straw hat, dark jacket and pants, white shirt without collar, seated, possibly in front of a blackboard with chalk writing, 156704 (Item 2514)
- older, balding, white mustache, beard, sideburns, gray colored work shirt, seated by a window, holding a dark colored felt hat in lap, 156703 (Item 2515)
- middle aged to older, spiky medium light hair, trim mustache and beard, striped jacket, gray colored work shirt, seated with newspaper, plants in background, 156702 (Item 2516)
- middle aged, standing, balding, medium dark thick mustache, print shirt, ribbon tie, suspenders, holding a bottle of dark liquid, standing a shop, possibly a printer, images hanging on brick wall in background, 156701 (Item 2517)
- young man, white or very light colored work shirt, pants, sailor's cap, seated on bench in front of stone wall covered with ivy next to a bucket, holding a bottle brush cleaning a milk bottle, 156700 (Item 2518)
- middle aged man in straw hat with dark band, white mustache, striped shirt, light colored suspenders, standing in what might be a dock, appears to be emptying a wooden box of dried fish, 1917; 156699 (Item 2519)
  in ink, DU's handwriting, on back of mounting board: The Evening Work, Doris U. Jaeger, 129 West 86th St., N.Y. City
- middle aged, dark felt hat, light colored shirt, suspenders, seated, cut stone wall in background, almost smiling, 156698 (Item 2520)
- young, dark or very tan complexion, standing outside in front of windowsill, scruffy overalls, cap, curly medium dark hair, 156697 (Item 2521)
- middle aged, white beard, mustache, dark felt hat, seated with cane or tool handle, work shirt, suspenders, 156696 (Item 2522)
- older, fine white hair, very long beard, sideburns, tanned, lined face, white shirt, suspenders, seated, 156695 (Item 2523)
  #2523-2530 same subject
- older, fine white hair, very long beard, sideburns, tanned, lined face, white shirt, suspenders, seated, 156694 (Item 2524)
- older, fine white hair, very long beard, sideburns, tanned, lined face, white shirt, suspenders, seated with book, 156693 (Item 2525)
- older, fine white hair, very long beard, sideburns, tanned, lined face, white shirt, suspenders, seated with book, 156692 (Item 2526)
- older, fine white hair, very long beard, sideburns, tanned, lined face, white shirt, suspenders, seated with book, 156691 (Item 2527)
- older, fine white hair, very long beard, sideburns, tanned, lined face, white shirt, suspenders, seated with book, 156690 (Item 2528)